Guide to the Joel Garreau Papers, 1954-1994
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: Edge City, 1959-February 1994
  - NJ Culture, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    A pamphlet about New Jersey theater.
  - New Jersey Port Liberte, November 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    The November 1988 issue of Builder, the Magazine of the National Association of Home Builders.
  - Employment Figures New Jersey, August-September 1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Documents and notes about employment in New Jersey.
  - New Jersey Vacations, January 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Magazines, pamphlets and maps about vacation options in New Jersey.
  - I-80 I-287 Corridors Development, September 1988 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    An overview of residential development opportunities along the Interstate 80 and 287 corridor in New Jersey.
  - New York: Housing, March-September 1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Articles about the New York City housing markets.
  - I-78 Corridor Market Report, June 1988 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Overview of residential development opportunities along the interstate 78 corridor in New Jersey and a brochure for New Jersey's Gateway Region.
  - Lehigh Valley Jobs, May 1988-July 1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Articles and notes about employment in the Allentown/Bethlehem, Pennsylvania area.
  - Long Island: Lesser Market Report, August-October 1988 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    A Market Validation and a Market Analysis in Long Island.
  - Long Island Census Bureau Information, January 1990 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    An article about growth.
  - Sources Princeton, April 1989 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Notes about Princeton, New Jersey and Willard Conference roundtable participants descriptions.
  - Princeton Marriott, Undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    A flier for a Mother's Day celebration at a Marriott hotel in Princeton, New Jersey.
  - US1 Directory Companies List, May 1985-April 1989 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    Two newspapers about US Route 1 corridor in New Jersey.
  - Princeton US1 Newspapers, October 1987-May 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Newspapers, correspondence, documents and miniature cassette tapes about US Route 1.
  - "The Future Version" New Jersey, March 1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Rough drafts of Garreau texts.
  - Bridgewater, NJ, December 1989 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Magazines and promotional material for a businesses in New Jersey.
  - Notes on NJ, March 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Notes and transcripts of notes about New Jersey
  - Notes - Northern NJ - Roger Garreau, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Notes about Northern New Jersey and Roger Garreau.
  - Paris La Defense, July 1989-August 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Notes and documents about La Defense, a group of office buildings near Paris, France.
  - Philly Market, January-May 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Articles and documents about development of markets in the Philadelphia area.
  - Phoenix, December 1990 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Notes, business cards, notebooks and contact lists about Phoenix, Arizona. Also included is "Beyond the Urban Landscape" edited by Rutherford H. Platt and George Macinko.
  - Crystal City, July 1983-January 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Newspaper articles, promotional booklets, fact sheets, demographic information, maps and notes from and about the Charles E. Smith Companies and development in Crystal City, Virginia.
  - Fairfax Center Pino's Cafe (Box 17, Folder 2)
    A business card from Pino's Cafe in Fairfax, Virginia.
  - Little Rocky Run, January 1986-June 1987 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Documents, sales figures, organizational charts, contact lists, newsletters, maps, a cassette tape, fact sheets and a notebook about Little Rocky Run, a planned community in Fairfax, Virginia.
  - Houston Press Entertainment News, April 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Two issues of the Houston Press Entertainment News.
  - Dallas Observer, May 1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    An issue of the Dallas Observer.
  - North Houston - Schools, August 1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    A booklet and correspondence about schools in Houston, Texas.
  - West Houston, June 1986 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Documents from the West Houston Association
  - Texas Architect Magazine, November 1990-December 1991 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    The 1990/91 Texas Architect Magazine Editorial Calendar and Closing Dates.
  - The Woodlands, June 1986-October 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Articles and notes about The Woodlands, a planned community near Houston, Texas. Also included is "Woodlands New Community: An Ecological Inventory".
  - The Woodlands, October 1986-January 1988 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Documents and information about the Woodlands, a planned community near Houston, Texas.
  - Houston New Yorker Piece, January 1989 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    A New Yorker article about empty office space in Houston, Texas.
  - Houston Tourist Guide, May 1990 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    American Institute of Architecture Quickguide to Houston, restaurants, sightseeing and more.
  - Houston: The Galleria, January 1988-May 1990 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Notes, documents, maps, brochures and business cards about the Galleria mall in Houston Texas.
  - Houston CBD Map, Undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    A map of the Houston central business district.
  - Mickey Leland International Airlines Building (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Documents about the Mickey Leland International Airlines Building at the Houston Airport.
  - Notes-Houston, Undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Notes about Houston, Texas.
  - Ultra Magazine, May 1990 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    The May 1990 issue of Ultra Magazine.
  - Texas Cultura, May 1990 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    A menu, a flier, a coupon and a brochure about different things in Houston, Texas.
  - Project Houston, May-July 1990 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    A book of designs for development in Houston, Texas.
  - San Francisco, Undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Notes about San Francisco.
  - Asian Indians San Francisco, May 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    A Washington Post Article by Joel Kotkin "Asian Indians in California Spotlight After Years in Shadows".
  - Notes, Undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - December 1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    A letter to Garreau from Lynette Tanner, the Executive Director of Contra Costa Centre.
  - Pleasanton Notes, November 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Transcripts of notes about Pleasanton.
  - Walnut Creek Notes, November 1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Transcripts of notes about Walnut Creek.
  - Tapes, Undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Cassette tapes with recordings of notes about Alexander, Callahan, Pleasanton and Walnut Creek.
  - Costra Centre (Box 18, Folder 8)
    A business card, project profiles, a planning summary and a map of the Pleasant Hill Bart Station Area in Contra Costa County, California.
  - San Jose Mercury News, July 1986 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Articles from the San Jose Mercury News.
  - Contra Costa County, June 1988-August 1989 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Documents about growth in Contra Costa County, California.
  - Contra Costa County, July 1986-August 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Documents, business cards, correspondence, contact information and newspaper articles about real estate in Contra Costa County, California.
  - Contra Costa County - Alex Mehran, October 1989-March 1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Newspaper articles about and the transcript of an interview with Alex Mehran.
  - San Ramon - Architecture, October 1989 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    A San Francisco Examiner article about suburban revitalization.
  - Bishop Ranch, June-October 1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Promotional materials, newsletters and fact sheets about a business park in the San Francisco Bay Area called Bishop Ranch.
  - San Francisco - Oakland Stats, June-August 1989 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Documents, correspondence, maps, articles and a comparison of the markets in San Francisco and Oakland, California.
  - Pleasant Hill, August 1983-August 1989 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Documents about a proposed Bay Area Rapid Transit station for Pleasant Hill, a planned community in California.
  - Bay Area 1 of 6, November 1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    A group of documents about real estate, economy, employment and growth rate in the San Francisco Bay Area.
  - Bay Area 2 of 6, May 1989 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Bay Area 3 of 6, March 1986 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Bay Area 4 of 6, October 1988 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Bay Area 5 of 6, May 1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bay Area 6 of 6, February 1984 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Silicon Valley, June 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    A San Jose Mercury News article about Silicon Valley.
  - George Mason Chronology, June 1964-June 1983 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Notes and newspaper articles about the history of George Mason University. Also included is a list of highlights of GMU's history.
  - Atlanta Regional Commission, March 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    The March 1990 issue of Action, the Atlanta Regional Commission's newsletter.
  - Bridgeport Development, November 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Notes and documents about consumer focus groups in Georgia.
  - John C. Portman, Jr. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    An article from Sky magazine about John C. Portman, Jr.
  - Atlanta Clips (Journal Constitution), June 1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Books of newspaper articles about the shaping of Atlanta.
  - Trends Stats Jobs, December 1987 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    An Atlanta Region Forecast for trends, stats and jobs.
  - Transformation of Metro Atlanta's Business Landscape, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    "Suburban Downtowns and the Transformation of Metropolitan Atlanta's Business Landscape" by Truman A. Hartshorn and Peter O. Muller.
  - Homebuyers - Stats, April 1990 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Atlanta Journal and Constitution articles about buying and selling homes in the Atlanta, Georgia area.
  - Audrey Moore, July 1989 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    A Washington Post article about Audrey Moore.
  - Distance Between Texas Cities, Undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    A table of distances between cities in and around Texas.
  - Dallas: American Indian Art Celebration, May-September 1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Business cards, fliers, pamphlets and programs about American Indian art.
  - Texas Monthly Magazine, January 1988 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    The January 1988 issue of Texas Monthly Magazine.
  - Cartwright, Garry BRadley, January 1988 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    A transcript of notes about Gary Bradley.
  - Market Square Park Project, Undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
    A pamphlet for the Market Square Park Project in Houston.
  - Houston Business Section, May 1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    The Business Section of the May 14, 1990 issue of The Houston Post.
  - Milan - Galleria, April 1990 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    A Washington Post article about the Galleria in Milan by Stephen R. Conn.
  - Post Oak Area, Undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
    Bibliographic data on development of Post Oak area.
  - Dallas Notebooks, May 1990 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    A notebook about Dallas, Texas.
  - The Woodlands Notebook, Undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
    A notebook about the Woodlands, a planned community near Houston, Texas. See also box 12, folder 5 and box 17, folder 9.
  - Las Colinas - notebook, February 1988 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    A notebook about Las Colinas, in Houston, Texas.
  - Texas - San Antonio, Undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
    Notes about San Antonio, Texas.
  - Houston Notebooks, January 1988-May 1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Six notebooks about Houston, Texas.
  - Houston R/UDAT, April 1990 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    A document from the American Institute of Architecture's Houston Regional Urban Design Assistance Team and a note to Garreau.
  - Dallas Notes, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Notes about Dallas, Texas.
  - Dallas, Undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    An article about Dallas, Texas from Community Access Magazine.
  - Las Colinas, September 1985-May 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Promotional material, maps, a fact sheet, brochures and magazines about Las Colinas in Texas. Also included is a list of companies in Las Colinas.
  - Las Colinas: NYT Clip, January 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    A New York Times article about Las Colinas.
  - AIA Convention, May 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Newspapers, pamphlets, newspapers and programs from and about the 1990 American Institute of Architecture Convention.
  - Austin: Future Development; market analysis, November 1989 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    A market opportunity analysis of Austin, Texas.
  - Dallas Market Analysis, December 1989-October 1993 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Market Opportunity Analysis of the Dallas/Fort Worth region and an supplement to the Dallas Morning News.
  - Exxon - Dallas (Box 20, Folder 10)
    An article about Exxon from the Dallas Times Herald.
  - The Houston Post, March 1992 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Newspaper articles from the Houston Post about Houston, Texas.
  - Houston Sources, January 1989-August 1992 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Notes, magazine articles and correspondence about Houston, Texas.
  - Houston: Market Analysis, August 1989 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Market Opportunity Analysis of Houston, Texas.
  - Houston Press, March 1990 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    The March 8, 1990 issue of Houston Press News and Entertainment Weekly.
  - Commercial Office Market, June 1990 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    An office market overview of the Submarket Area in Irvine, California.
  - Orange County Office Market, June 1990 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    Correspondence and articles about the Orange County Office Market.
  - Evan and Ann Maxwell, Undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Notes about Evan and Ann Maxwell.
  - Orange Coast Magazine, June 1986-July 1990 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Newspaper and magazine articles about Irvine, California.
  - Irvine, January 1970-January 1990 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Notes, newspaper articles and business cards about Irvine, California. Also included is the January 28, 1988 issue of the Irvine World News.
  - Irvine, January 1988 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Notes, evaluations, a fact sheet and promotional brochures for planned communities by the Irvine Company. Also included is the Business Outlook '88 section of the Orange County Register.
  - Coldwell Banker Commercial Real Estate Services, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    The Dade County Market Profile and Retail Market Study.
  - The Orange County Exopolis: A Contemporary Screen-Play, Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    "The Orange County Exopolis: A Contemporary Screen-Play" by Edward W. Soja.
  - October 1988-August 1991 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Documents and correspondence about Belz Enterprises. Also included is an article about suburban gridlock from the Geographical Review.
  - Irvine Community Planning (Box 21, Folder 5)
    A community planning article about Irvine, California.
  - Irvine Notes, May-June 1990 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Notes, note transcripts and notebooks about Irvine, California. Also included is a list of Los Angeles Metropolitan Core Areas.
  - Irvine Notes, June 1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Notes and transcripts of notes about Irvine, California.
  - Southern California: Community (Box 21, Folder 8)
    A draft of chapter eight of "Edge City", "Southern California: Community".
  - Yaohan Plaza Edgewater, NJ, September 1989 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Menus, pamphlets, business cards, promotional material, bus schedules, a newspaper article and fliers about Yaohan Plaza and Chinzan-So restaurant in Edgewater, New Jersey.
  - NJ Development Plan, July 1991 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    "Communities of Place" a book about development in New Jersey.
  - (Box 21, Folder 11)
    Books, a business card, tour guides and brochures about Morristown, New Jersey. Also included is the June 1989 issue of New Jersey Business Magazine.
  - The Hills Development, NJ, Undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
    A community driving map of the residential neighborhood the Hills in New Jersey.
  - New Jersey Labor Force, August 1989 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    State wide figures of the labor force in New Jersey.
  - NJ 100 Largest Employers, Undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
    A list of the 100 largest employers in New Jersey.
  - NYC Economy Growth, November 1989 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    A Business Week magazine article about the growth of the economy in New York City.
  - NJ Growth Corridors Book, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    "New Jersey Growth Corridors" by George Sternlieb and Alex Schwartz
  - Somerset County, Undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    A promotional magazine, business card and a fact sheet about Somerset County, New Jersey.
  - Lebanon, NJ, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Promotional material for building complexes in Lebanon, New Jersey.
  - ULI Market Profiles, NY and NJ, June 1988 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, maps and market trends for New York and New Jersey from the Urban Land Institute.
  - Princeton, NJ, Undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    An article from Progressive Architecture about suburban sprawl.
  - Northern Jersey Labor Market, December 1984-August 1988 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Lists of major employers in Northern New Jersey and a regional labor market review.
  - NJ Wildlife, October 1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Notes and a Wall Street Journal article about wildlife in New Jersey.
  - NJ ATT, October 1939, March 1950-June 1956, June 1974-March 1990 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, articles, booklets, information packets, press releases and an annual report from and about ATandT Also included is employment figures for New Jersey.
  - New Brunswick, March 1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Newspaper articles about schools in New Brunswick, New Jersey.
  - NJ Education, November 1988-July 1989 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Newspaper articles about education in New Jersey.
  - Newark Center, May 1989 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    A promotional pamphlet for a building complex called Newark Center.
  - Civilizations, local, cultures, November 1988 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Notes and a newspaper article about a church in Tysons Corner, Virginia.
  - Corporate HQ Relocations, March 1988-February 1990 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Articles about the relocation of corporate headquarters.
  - The Arts, September 1988 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Newspaper articles about artists studios and performance spaces in Washington, D.C. Civilization, Local
  - The Arts, November 1986-December 1988 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    Documents and articles about humanities in America. Civilization, National
  - Spirituality, March 1989 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    A Washington Post article about development in Shenandoah Valley, Virginia. See box 22, folder 20. Civilization
  - Lawyers in Suburbs, May 1990 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    A Philadelphia Inquirer article about lawyers moving to firms in the suburbs. Civilization
  - Words Living Villages, June 1988-October 1990 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    An article about Living Villages, a newspaper published by Kentlands, a planned community, and "Architect Talk" by Nathan Silver.
  - Real Estate, Urban Economics, July 1989 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    "Current Publications of the Center For Real Estate and Urban Economics" from the Institute of Business and Economic Research.
  - Quality of Life, November 1988 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    The November 1988 issue of the ERC Report (Eastern Regional Conference of the Council of State Governments). Civilization, National
  - Trappists Lose Solitude, March 1989 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    An article about a development in Shenandoah Valley, Virginia. See box 22, folder 15. Civilization
  - Mall Fashion, July 1989 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    An article about fashion at malls. Civilization
  - Monster Mansions, May 1990 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    A Washington Post article about mansions. Civilizations
  - Principals of Design, June 1989 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    An article about design principles. Civilization, National
  - Diners Bob Giaimo, February 1989 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    Articles about Diners and Bob Giaimo. Civilization, Local
  - July 1982-May 1985, Character Documents Audrey Moore (Box 22, Folder 25)
    Articles about Audrey Moore.
  - History of Parks, July 1989 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    An article about planning and the history of parks. Theory
  - J. Herbers The New Heartland, August 1986 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    An excerpt from a book by John Herbers about the heartland and an article about the Urban Land Institute. Theory
  - Growth Management, October 1990 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    An article about growth and transportation in Northern Virginia. Theory
  - Coping with Growth, October 1991 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    An article about development and growth in Northern Virginia.
  - Global Boom, October 1989 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    An Atlantic article "The Coming Global Boom" by Charles Morris. Theory
  - The German Model, October 1988-January 1990 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    An article about growth and an article about traffic congestion. Theory
  - Landscape Space Ithaca, April 1981 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    "Space Is the American Mediator, or The Blocks of Ithaca: A Speculation" by Peter Smithson. Theory
  - Landscape Zelinsky, June 1987-February 1989 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    Articles by Wilbur Zelinsky about landscape and advertisements featuring landscape.
  - Governance, December 1988-January 1989 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    Documents, correspondence, and business cards from the National Association of Regional Councils about changing social and economic disparities in metropolitan areas.
  - Information Age, January 1988-January 1990 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    Articles about income inequality, globalism, technology and social life, the telephone industry, tomorrow's companies, and the information age. Theory
  - Indefensible Space, August 1978 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    An article about development of private space. Theory
  - Human Scale, Undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    A chapter, "The Optimum City" of a book, "Society on a Human Scale". Theory
  - Regional Challenges 21st Century, May 1991 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    "Regional Challenges in the 21st Century" by R. Scott Fosler. Theory
  - Population Movement (Box 23, Folder 3)
    >"Population and Employment Change in the U.S.: Past, Present, and Future" by John D. Kasandra. Theory
  - Parking Lot Design, February 1989 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    An article about parking lots. Theory
  - "The Nice", February-June 1989 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Notes, an article about the quality of life. Theory
  - Lewis Mumford, January-February 1990 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Two articles about Lewis Mumford. Theory
  - Marketing, November 1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    An article about the future of marketing. Theory
  - Leo Marx, April 1989 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    An article about The American Ideology of Space and an article about the environment. Theory
  - Socialist Utopian (Box 23, Folder 9)
    An excerpt from a book about Socialist Utopian theory. Theory
  - Telecommunications, July 1990 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Articles about fiber optic telecommunications. Theory
  - James Vance Realms, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    A excerpt from James Vance's book about the role of the city in the geography of civilization. Theory
  - Suburbia Residential, Undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
    Suburbia Re-examined, "The suburbs and how they grew" and "Turning the American City Inside Out". Theory
  - Suburbia Structural Change, June 1987 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    An article giving an overview of metropolitan structural change since 1947. Theory
  - Connecticut Fairfield County, Undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    A promotional magazine for Fairfield County, Connecticut.
  - Chicago Market Reports, October 1987 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Chicago Real Estate Market Reports.
  - Chicago (Box 23, Folder 16)
    Notes, articles and a map about Chicago, Illinois.
  - Ventura California, October 1991 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    An article about Orange County, California.
  - Third Harbor Tunnel I-90, June 1983 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    A summary report about a harbor tunnel in Boston, Massachusetts.
  - Sources: Glenn Miller, February 1989-February 1990 (Box 23, Folder 19)